### Steven E. Newton

Senior Software Engineer with deep expertise in modernizing legacy systems. Proven track record in migrating and realigning heritage systems to improve platform stability while enhancing internal and partner user needs and long-term maintainability.

#### PROFESSIONAL HIGHLIGHTS

Experienced in testing, producing clear documentation, and communicating business needs. Demonstrated mastery of a wide range of languages and frameworks, large-scale distributed systems delivered at scale, and driving maintainable and responsive code.

Quick to grasp unfamiliar codebases, apply inventive troubleshooting skills, and discover and analyze anomalies across complex system environments

Proven track record in mentoring both technical and soft skills, team building, and enabling effective collaboration

Keen to reconcile technical and organizational value to meet organizational needs, contribute to core business functions, and align with business goals

Enjoys simplifying complex topics, mentoring, guiding to growth, solving problems, and improving existing code.

#### RELEVANT SKILLS

- Languages: Go, Java, JavaScript
- Frameworks and Persistence: passport-js, gorilla-mux, dropwizard, redis, major relational databases
- · OS and environments: Linux, OS X, AWS, Docker, Kubernetes
- Coding environments: VS Code, IntelliJ, Eclipse
- Tools: git, maven, Jira

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE AND PROJECTS

# Senior Go Engineer - Eliassen - 2022 - 2023

Alaska Airlines Check-In Modernization Program

• Migrated the check-in experience from a third-party platform to modern, in-house Go in Kubernetes

### Senior Software Engineer, Team Lead - Xandr - 2018 - 2021

AppNexus Console and UXUA: Universal Xandr User Authentication

- Implemented federated single sign-on for the core product website with SAML and OpenID Connect
- Extended federated single sign-on across all customer-facing applications with SAML and OpenID Connect. Federated identity management, identity mapping, and account mapping.

### Software Engineer - Treetop Commons, LLC - 2017

NobleHour and Collaboratory

• Corrected, improved, and stabilized SAML2 service provider implementation, s3 asset management; refined and expanded cucumber integration tests; implemented Go-based microservices

## Lead Software Engineer - Janrain, Inc - 2012 - 2015

Social login platform built on a variety of technologies and deployed wholly on AWS

• Migrated Java Spring application persistence layer from Amazon SimpleDB to redis, and raised uptime of key component to five 9s

### INTERESTS/HOBBIES/AWARDS

- Photography Award winning film photographer specializing in black and white techniques
- Guitar

#### **EDUCATION**

University of Texas, Austin — Austin, Texas Bachelor of Arts, Journalism